IAN CLARK

Chicago, IL IanClark.FullStack@gmail.com

8505271749 | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

Full stack web developer, capitalizing on customer-service driven sales experience, design proficiency and full stack web development education at Northwestern University. Excited to expand my experience of new and improved programming paradigms within a fast-paced, quality driven company culture.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS3, WordPress, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Chart Js, Handlebars

Back End: Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, ORM

Applications: GitHub, Postman, Insomnia, Photoshop, Illustrator

PROJECTS

Note Taking Application - Repository, Deployed

Full Stack Web Developer

- Drafted and developed a full-stack application for the sole purpose of creating, reading, updating and deleting notes.
- Languages: JavaScript, Node, Express

E-Commerce Backend End Application - Repository

Backend Developer

- Drafted and developed e-commerce style database, by implementing object relational mapping paradigms.
- Languages: Node.js, Sequelize, MySQl, Express, ORM, Illustrator

Weather Dashboard - Repository, Deployed

Sole Author / Web Developer

- Drafted and developed application to deliver current and forecasted weather data using Openweather Api services.
- Implemented strategies to increase ease of user experience using local storage. Incorporated relevant design elements including a parametric font, varying in style based on the air quality index of a user's current location.
- Languages: ¡Query, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Openweather Geocoding and Onecall Api

EXPERIENCE

Eden in Chicago - Fine Dining Server

2018 - 2020

Ensuring exceptional customer satisfaction and efficient service..

- Story-telling through fluent descriptions of each course, as well as their respective wine pairings.
- Repeatedly noted as a leader with excellent job performance and guest relations

Verifone - EMV Installation Technician

2016 - 2017

Clearwater, Fl

- Increased customer experience by conducting personable, successful and prompt remote installations.
- Collaborated with team members to complete corporation specific software updates across North America.
- Maintained virtual security best practices while working within virtual software environments.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development - Northwestern University

January 2021 - Present

Chicago, IL

Digital Media - Gulf Coast State College

2016 - 2018

Panama City, Fl